# Jon Urry

# JavaScript Web Developer

mobile: 07986 371 299 - email: jon@urry.me - portfolio: jon.urry.me github: github.com/jonurry - linkedin: linkedin.com/in/jonurry - twitter: twitter.com/jonurry

## **Profile**

Customer-focused, technically proficient, pragmatic software developer with 21+ years commercial experience. Seeking a new challenge and retraining as a full-stack JavaScript web developer using open source technologies.

Designed and implemented software used by: BP, ExxonMobil, General Motors, Ford, Hyundai, Kia, Peugeot, Citroën, Chrysler, LG, Jaguar, Land Rover, Bentley, Aston Martin, US Air Force and multiple airlines including Lufthansa, Cathay Pacific, Air China and Alitalia.

# **Skillset**

Languages: JavaScript, ES6, HTML, CSS, SASS, XML, Node, Jest, Bootstrap.

Tools: Git, GitHub, VS Code, Chrome Inspector, CodeKit, ESLint, Babel, Prettier, Atom, Slack, Assembla, UML.

Design: UX, UI, Responsive Design, Mobile First, Sketch, Flex, Grid, SVG, Animation, Web Fonts. Process: Design Patterns, Unit Testing, Test-driven Development, Agile Methodologies, Scrum. e-Commerce: WordPress, WooCommerce, Storefront, Stripe, Print On-Demand, Drop Shipping. Marketing: SEO, Analytics, Drip, Keywords, Facebook Shopping / Ads, Social Media, Ranking.

Database: SQL Server, SSRS, SSIS, MySQL, Oracle PL/SQL, Performance Optimisation.

# **Projects**

- IOTA: Designed web app and implemented database for Bluetooth interoperability testing that helped attract new customers more than doubling annual revenue to £2 million.
- Black Box: Abstract board game which simulates shooting rays into a black box to deduce the locations of 'atoms' hidden inside.
- Velo Studio: Online e-commerce store selling cycling inspired t-shirts with panache!
- Wedding: Two websites, one pre-wedding and one post-wedding.
- Eloquent JS Solutions: My solutions to the exercises set in the 3rd edition of eloquent JavaScript

# Recommendations

+ 19 more on LinkedIn

"He's a natural problem solver and is able to take on and successfully deliver some of the most challenging engagements out there... I can't recommend Jon enough." Jason Spencer Director, Financial Advisory, Deloitte

"He has exceptional analytical skills and could always be trusted to find elegant and creative solutions when presented with complex technical problems." Stuart May Director, Product Management, Expedia.com

"Jon is an outstanding software developer who led the development of the most important product in our portfolio..." Dimitris Lyras Managing Director, Ulysses Systems

"Jon can define and create business technology solutions that will deliver competitive advantage." Andor Miles-Board Marketing & Business Development Manager, NextGen Technology

### Education

MSc Scientific Computing - University of Huddersfield

Postgraduate Diploma Software Technology - University of Hull

BSc Physics, Associate Royal College of Science - Imperial College of Science, Technology and Medicine, London

### **Achievements**

- Successfully led and managed a distributed team of software engineers in London, Mumbai and Chandigarh, delivering features on schedule and at a significantly reduced cost.
- Solved challenging and complex business problems. E.g. Interoperability of software versions. Others had abandoned this problem in the past only for me to succeed.
- Designed and implemented dozens of SQL Server reports to delivering business-critical information ondemand saving many hours of work every week across the company.
- Designed and implemented an audit solution that enabled process inefficiencies to be highlighted and provided real metrics for accurate customer quotes.
- Implemented many optimisations to dramatically increase software performance. E.g. improving complex filtering process from 100 minutes to less than 10 seconds.
- Realised fully automated build tool. Significantly reduced labour costs (converting a 2-day manual task to a 1-hour automated task) and improved quality by reducing human error.
- Helped to turn around failing software project to automatically test in-car system interoperability.

# **Experience**

### Consultant Software Engineer, Agile Web Limited (2009 - 2018)

Providing business critical software solutions to a Bluetooth interoperability testing company.

- Responsible for architecting, designing, developing and delivering software solutions to bring commercial savings and competitive advantage to clients.
- Creating XML generator for Ford Motor Company to power their global customer-facing websites.

### Product Manager, Ulysses Systems (2006 - 2009)

Ulysses Systems is an award-winning provider of enterprise business intelligence software to the marine industry. Customers included: BP, ExxonMobil, Bourbon, Exmar and V.Ships.

- Responsible for 'Core Technologies' platform. Split 70% design/coding and 30% management.
- Promoted agile methodologies and helped define new and improved processes.

### Team Leader, Ulysses Systems (2000 - 2006)

- Led a team of software engineers who envisioned, designed and implemented a multi-user document management system from scratch.
- Designed and developed a UI framework. Reusable solution saved many weeks of development work and gave the product a consistent look and operation.

#### Senior Software Engineer, Ulysses Systems (1999 - 2000)

Improving legacy software for the marine industry.

### Software Engineer, Integrated Sales Systems (1999)

CRM software for the healthcare, pharmaceutical and insurance sectors. Company acquired by Vodafone.

### Analyst Programmer, TRO Learning UK (1996 - 1999)

World-leading computer-based training (CBT) software company supplying aerospace training solutions to commercial and military organisations. Company acquired by The Vega Group.

• Designed, implemented and tested CBT applications, incl. \$250k flight simulator for US Air Force.